If you remember back to our function that we built in the last video,
在上个视频中我们构建了一个函数
this one right here, our getMetricMetaInfo,
也就是这个 getMetricMetaInfo
there are two types of inputs that we're going to be using,
在该函数中有两种输入 稍后我们将用到
either a stepper which is composed of two different buttons,
一个是步进器 它由两种不同的按钮组成
basically a button to increment and a button to decrement, or a slider,
一个递增按钮和一个递减按钮
which is typically between one and a specific number,
还有一个是滑块 通常位于 1 和特定数字之间
in this case 24, and in our eat case it's between one and 10.
这里是 24 对于饮食类别 则是 1 到 10 之间
So, with those two types of inputs,
对于这两种类型的输入
there are going to be three different methods that we're going to need on
我们需要在类中使用三种方法
our class in order to be able to modify those inputs, basically.
才能修改这些输入
So, our state is going to consist of five different things.
因此我们的 state 将包含五项不同的内容
We're going to have run, bike, basically a metric for everything that we're tracking,
也就是 run bike 和其他要跟踪的指标
and each of them are going to start off at zero.
每项指标都从 0 开始
Because again, the whole goal of this component is to get
因为该组件的最终目标是
the users triathlon data plus their sleep and eat data for the specific day.
获取用户在某一天的铁人三项数据和睡眠及饮食数据
So, when they're filling out this form,
当他们填写表格时
the metrics that we want to be tracking are these five metrics right here.
我们要跟踪的指标就是这五项指标
So, first let's go ahead and we will create
首先 我们将在这里
an increment method right here and this is going to be for our run,
创建一个 increment 方法
bike and swim metrics.
专门用于 run bike 和 swim 指标
So, when we invoke this we're going to pass in the metric.
当我们调用该方法时 我们将传入 metric
And then what we need to do is,
然后我们需要
we need to get the max that the metric could
获取该指标的最大值
be as well as how much we should increment by which is the step.
以及递增幅度 也就是步长
And we're going to get those from our getMetricMetaInfo function that we created,
我们将从创建的 getMetricMetaInfo 函数中获取这些信息
passing in the specific metric.
传入特定的指标
And then what we're going to do is,
然后我们将
we will call setState.
调用 setState
So, we're going to update our local component states.
我们将更新本地组件状态
When you call setState and you pass it a function,
调用 setState 时 传入一个函数
what you get is the current state and then what we want to do is,
并获得当前状态
we want to say the count is going to be whatever the specific property is of the metrics.
然后我们将 count 设为指标的特定属性
So, if it was bike then the count in this case would be zero,
如果是 bike 那么这里的 count 将为 0
because state at bike is equal to zero.
因为骑行状态等于 0
And then what we want to do is,
然后我们将
we want to increment it by whatever the step is,
按照相应的步长递增
which again we're getting from this function.
同样从此函数中获取
So now what we want to do is,
现在我们将
we want to return a new object and the object that you returned
返回一个新的对象
from setState is going to be merged with the current state.
setState 返回的对象将与当前状态合并
So, we want to say, go ahead and keep all of the state properties that are already there,
因此保留已经存在的所有属性
but whatever this metric is we want to update it,
但是无论该指标是什么
and what we want it to be is,
我们都想更新它
we'll say if count is greater than the max value,
如果 count 大于最大值
then the metric is now just going to be whatever the max value is.
则指标现在将是相应的最大值
And if it isn't, then it's just going to be count.
如果不大于最大值 则是 count
So again what we're doing here is,
这段代码的作用是
we are updating our state.
更新状态
All of the state properties are staying the same,
所有状态属性保持不变
but this one metric is going to update.
但是这个指标将更新
And if it's bigger than the count or if it's bigger than the max,
如果 count 大于最大值
we don't want it to go above that,
我们不希望超过最大值
so it's just the max and if it's not,
因此直接设为 max 如果不大于最大值
then it's just going to be this new count.
则是这个新的 count
So, we need to do this exact same thing except we are going to decrement.
我们将执行完全一样的流程 但是现在是递减操作
So I'm just going to go ahead and paste this in.
将这段代码粘贴过来
We will call this decrement.
称为 decrement
And then now what we're going to do,
现在我们不再需要 max 和 step
is we don't need max and step because we're going to be subtracting.
因为我们将执行减法操作
So, I'm just going to copy this.
复制这些代码
We'll delete both of these.
删掉这些代码
So, we're going to call setState. We want to go ahead
我们将调用 setState
and get the count just like we did above here.
并像在上面那样获得 count
But, our count instead of doing plus step,
但是现在不是加上步长
what we're going to do is say minus step.
而是减去步长
And then now, just as we did down here,
然后就像在下面这样
we're going to say we want to return everything.
我们要返回所有内容
We want the state to be exactly how it is.
我们希望状态保持不变
But, this specific metric is going to be, and then we'll say,
但是将更新这个指标
if count is less than zero,
如果 count 小于 0
then we want it to just be zero,
则设为 0
and if not, then we want it to be whatever this count is.
如果不小于 0 则设为这个 count
So, this is very similar to what we're doing right here,
因此和这里的操作很相似
except now we're just making sure that we're not going below zero.
只是现在要确保不能小于 0
And, now the very last thing we need to do is this,
最后要执行的操作是
increment and decrement work for these three metrics right here,
我们为这三个指标创建了 increment 和 decrement 功能
but we're going to be using a slider for sleep and eat.
但是我们将为 sleep 和 eat 创建滑块
So, let's go ahead and create a slide method right here
在这里创建一个 slide 方法
and it's going to take in the specific metric as well as the new value.
并传入具体的指标以及新的值
And then, what we will do is,
然后我们将
we will call setState and then we want to return an object and we will just say
调用 setState 并返回一个对象
the new metric is now going to have a value of
新的指标将是
whatever the second argument we passed then to the slide function was.
我们在 slide 函数中传入的第二个参数
And now this looks good.
看起来不错
So, we do have an extra comma right here,
不过在第 24 行有个多余的逗号
on line 24, that we don't need,
这个逗号不需要
you probably caught that.
你可能已经发现了这个逗号
Now we should be good.
现在应该没问题了